Cinthia Fontoura de Souza

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Brazilian | Dublin 9 | cinthiafontouras@gmail.com +353 83 385 9229 | <u>Portfolio</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Github</u>

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a Junior Software Developer enrolled in a Full Stack software development program at Code Institute, where I am learning HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Python. In addition, I am studying UX/UI and web accessibility. I am actively seeking career change opportunities as a junior software developer. Working 13 years as a Chef, I had the chance to develop my teamwork skills in restaurants where I trained people, managed small teams and worked on my own when I ran my bakery.

KEY SKILLS

• Languages: HTML, CSS, Sass, JavsScript, Python.

Databases: MongoDB
Libraries: JQuery
Version Control: Git, GitHub.

• Frameworks: Bootstrapproject Terra Matter

Others: VS Code, Gitpod, Node.js, Command-line, npm.

• **Design:** Figma, Adobe Photoshop, Design Thinking, UX/UI principles.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Jan 2022 - Jan 2023 Code Institute

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development (with React.js) Credit Rated by The University of the West of Scotland Merit grade received on the first three assignments.

Aug 2021 - Dec 2021 Ibat College Dublin

Professional Diploma in UX/UI Design

Distinction grade received

PORTFOLIO PROJECTS

- 1. **Restaurant 104** | Live site | GitHub | HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, Hosting Ireland/cPanel.
- 2. Rock Paper Scissors Game | Live site | GitHub | HTML, CSS, Python, Gitpod, Heroku.
- 3. JavaScript Quiz | Live site | GitHub | HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Gitpod, GitHub Pages.
- 4. Portfolio | Live site | GitHub | Figma, HTML, CSS, Git, Netlify.

COLLABORATIVE PROJECTS

- 1. **Emojourney** | <u>Live site</u> | <u>GitHub</u> | Agile Methodology, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Git, GitHub, GitHub Pages.
- 2. Terra Matter | Live site | GitHub | HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Git, GitHub, GitHub Pages.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Nov 2021 - Present

Richmond Restaurant, Dublin, Ireland

Chef de Partie

- Michelin Bib Gourmand Restaurant since 2018.
- Plating the meals and desserts.
- Preparation following the HACCP.
- Keep the kitchen clean and tidy.

May 2021 - Present

Restaurant 104, Dublin, Ireland

Web Designer

- Design and develop their <u>website</u>.
- HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, Git, cPanel.
- Ongoing maintenance.

Dec 2020 - Nov 2021

Restaurant 104, Dublin, Ireland

Chef de Partie

- Fill up the HACCP control sheets.
- Control and organisation of kitchen stock.
- Preparation and plating meals and deserts.
- Keep the kitchen clean and tidy.

GENERAL SKILLS

Soft Skills:

Creativity, Teamwork, Critical thinking, Troubleshooting, Curiosity, Learning from others, Open-mindedness, Empathy, Flexibility, Leadership, Patience, Attention to detail, Collaboration, Communication, Eager to learn.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Stamp 4 (family member) visa.
- Portuguese (Native), English (Intermediate).
- <u>1st Place</u> in the Code Institute's World Emoji Day Hackathon, July 2022.

CERTIFICATES

Google Careers:

- Technical Support Fundamentals (20 hours)
- The Bits and Bytes of Computer Networking (25 hours)

Udemy:

- Web Design for Web Developers: Build Beautiful Websites! (2.5 hours)
- Build Responsive Real World Websites with HTML and CSS (37.5 hours)

Alura (PT-BR certificates):

- Training:
 - HTML and CSS (46 hours)
 - Web Accessibility (20 hours)
- Courses:
 - Programming logic I: create programs with Javascript and HTML (16 hours)
 - Python: starting with the language (12 hours)
 - Classic games part 1: Pong with Javascript (6 hours)
 - o Computer Architecture: Behind How Your Program Works (8 hours)

- Sass and Compass: Uncomplicating CSS (8 hours)
- Flexbox: place elements on the screen (9 hours)
- HTTP: Understanding the web behind the scenes (14 hours)
- CSS Grid: simplifying layouts (8 hours)
- o CSS Architecture: Uncomplicating the Problems (8 hours)
- JavaScript: Exploring the Language (10 hours)
- Responsive Layouts: working with mobile layouts (7 hours)
- Style Guide: Assembling Pages with Components (8 hours)
- Sass: The CSS with superpowers (10 hours)
- JavaScript for the Web: Create Dynamic Pages (10 hours)
- SASS: Syntactically Spectacular CSS (8 hours)
- Linux I: knowing and using the terminal (4 hours)
- o Git and Github: Control and Share Your Code (6 hours)
- Figma: Visual design of a mobile site (10 hours)
- UX: Understand User Experience (8 hours)
- Design Thinking: enabling solutions (8 hours)

References Upon Request